

CONTACT

610.772.1279

sara.coren@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saracoren

https://github.com/saracoren

https://saracoren.github.io/ Portfolio

SKILLS

WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, APIs, Mongo, Materialize, Bootstrap, Heroku, Ruby on Rails, SQL, React, GitHub, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Canva

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering General Assembly

Masters in General and Special Education (Gr. 1-6) Touro College

Masters in Geography and Environmental Science University College London

Bachelors in Geology with a Minor in Sociology The College of William & Mary

INTERESTS

UX Design, Innovation, Traveling, Hiking, Kayaking, Volunteering, Cross-Stitching

PROFILE

I am a product driven full stack web developer excited about expanding my knowledge base in the field. I have been a life-long learner and elementary educator as well as a researcher, geoscientist and humanitarian. I am passionate about using my web development skills and human centered approach in design to help people around the world access information to improve the quality of their lives.

EXPERIENCE

User Interface Engineering | Junior Web Developer

January 2020 - June 2020

North Andover, Massachusetts

- Code responsive HTML emails, write custom CSS, schedule email campaigns in MailChimp and track the results of A/B testing
- Utilize WordPress and Expression Engine CMS to publish content on the web
- Manage social media posts in Sprout and CoSchedule
- Write extensive documentation in Notion for future interns to reference

answerYES Consulting | Web Development Intern

June 2019 - January 2020

Stamford, Connecticut

- Worked with a small team to redesign and redevelop a WordPress website for a non-profit organization helping underserved kids in the Bridgeport community
- Gained experience with information architecture, site mapping, writing a custom child theme, working with WP plugins, Photoshop, Adobe XD, and Dreamweaver

Signature Brand Factory | Web Development Intern

October 2019 - December 2019 Southington, Connecticut

- Customized code on several different WordPress websites for various clients using the Divi theme
- Used Photoshop to optimize photos for web development

Rectory School | Grade 2 & 3 Lead Teacher

August 2017 - June 2018

Pomfret, Connecticut

- Instructed a mixed class of 2nd and 3rd grade students across all subject areas
- Wrote original curriculum and developed project based science lessons, activities and projects to help students connect their learning to the real world

Windham Public Schools | Substitute Math Coach and STEM Teacher

August 2015 - June 2017

Windham, Connecticut

- Worked as a math coach serving students in Grades K-5 with instructional support and providing data collection
- Substitute taught in various STEM classrooms in grades pre-K to 8

New York City Dept. of Education | Grade 4 Lead Teacher

August 2010 - June 2018

New York, New York

- Worked in a small coaching group for Literacy Coaches with Columbia Teachers College staff developers
- Served as president of the School Leadership Team and gave professional development presentations to staff